ONG MEI GEE

Address: Kuala Terengganu, Terengganu, Malaysia, Mobile: +60 17-9150809; Email: meigeeong@gmail.com, LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/ong-mei-gee-3a03541ab

Profile Summary

Analytical research professional with over 5 years of experience in data analysis. Proficient in IBM SPSS and Excel, with a background in biomedical and nutritional-based research. Currently engaged in a part-time role and independent learning of data analytics tools, including MySQL and Power BI.

Career Experience

Postgraduate researcher Universiti Sains Malaysia (2016-2023)

1. Data collection

- Collaborated with health professionals from Obesity Clinic, and implemented behavioural weight loss quasi-experimental for various populations, including obese patients.
- Conducted extensive data collection, including physical activity level, quality of life questionnaires, biochemical, nutrient, and body composition assessments.
- Collected findings for baseline, post-intervention, and follow-up evaluations.

2. Data Analysis and Visualisation

- Leading to a primary finding of > 5% body weight reduction in the test group.
- Employed T-tests to compare means difference between two groups.
- Conducted descriptive statistics (measures of central tendency and dispersion).
- Analyzed median (IQR) using Mann-Whitney U Test, Wilcoxon Signed-Rank Test.
- Analyzed multiple time points using repeated measures ANOVA.
- Created data visualisation (bar charts, line graph, histogram, scatter plot, box-plot, pivot tables).
- Performed data cleaning, such as removing duplicates and handling missing values, and used conditional formatting to highlight important findings using Microsoft Excel.
- Use One-way ANOVA with GraphPad Prism Software to compare the significant mean difference of blood glucose levels upon post-consumption of test foods.
- Completed an Intensive course in Basic Statistics and Research Methodology (2016).

3. As a part-time research and community facilitator, responsibilities included:

- Conducting focus group discussions and sensory evaluation of carbohydrate foods.
- Weight Loss Program for school children in National Secondary School, Kelantan.
- Managed grant projects to ensure compliance and effective budget management.
- Scientific writing, including research papers, grant proposals, and technical reports.

Research Assistant *Universiti Sains Malaysia* (2015-2016)

• Managed research grants, and conducted qualitative and quantitative studies, including focus group study, nutrient analysis, and USM-Human Ethics Application.

Postgraduate Researcher Universiti Sains Malaysia (2012-2013)

- Research proposal development, managed laboratory resources, including spectrophotometer, rotary evaporator, and ultrasonicator to ensure proper maintenance and calibration
- Utilised one-way ANOVA to measure mean differences for research outcomes.

Industrial Trainee (Undergraduate) *INFORMM*, *Penang (May-July 2011)*: Research Title: *Toxoplasma gondii*: In *Vivo* and In *Vitro* Culture, Antigen Preparation, and ELISA Optimization (2011); Completed with Certification of Industrial Training in Biotechnology and Management

Skills Summary

Tools: IBM SPSS, GraphPad Prism, Microsoft Excel, Words, Power point, Endnote writing tools **Language Proficiency Level:** Mandarin (4/5); English (4/5); Malay (4/5)

Education

Ph.D. in Nutrition, Universiti Sains Malaysia (Graduated, 2023)

M.Sc. in Medical Research, Universiti Sains Malaysia (Graduated, 2013), CGPA: 3.64/4.00 B.Sc. (Hons) in Biomedicine, Universiti Sains Malaysia (Graduated, 2012), CGPA: 3.36/4.00

Conferences and Publications

- 1. Detection of Anti-Amoebic Antibody Among the Senoi Aborigine in Sungai Siput, Perak
 - Oral Presenter, Biomedicine Symposium (2012)
- 2. Pharmacognostic and antioxidant properties of *Dracaena sanderiana leaves*
 - Best Presenter, 7th AMDI Postgraduate Scientific Seminar (2013)
 - Publications: Available at: https://www.mdpi.com/2076-3921/5/3/28
- 3. Elemental analyses of commercially available rice samples in Malaysia by using ICP-MS and SEM-EDX
 - Oral Presenter, IFOSAC Conference (2018)
 - Publications: Available at: https://www.asianjab.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/13.-AJAB-P27.pdf
- 4. Glycaemic index of commercially available brown rice in East Coast of Peninsular Malaysia.
 - Publications: Available at: https://eprints.usm.my/31496/1/WR_RJ_WAM_BHu_PW_WM_Brown_Rice_2016.pdf
- 5. The Impact of Combination of Behavioural Intervention and Nutrition Education with Brown Rice (COMBINE-BROWN) Weight Loss Program on Anthropometric Parameters in Overweight and Obese Adults (Abstract available at: https://erepo.usm.my/entities/publication/5106e40a-de67-4d4e-83e6-9e876afcb3e1)
 - Oral Presenter, MASO 2019 Scientific Conference on Obesity